Welcome brothers and sisters to another
Wednesday question and answer where we
open up with the ten commandments that
God had written for the whole world to
keep. Brother James,
>> yes sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maidervant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as
maid's servant, nor as ox, nor as ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I
read Exodus 20:es 1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Mhm.
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you keep your questions to a two
scripture maximum. But let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening, Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
Brother Jerome,
>> rest in peace.
>> Brother Julius,
>> good evening everybody.
>> Brother James,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. What is our
first question to kick off our program?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Detroit Troy Price asks, "Do angels have
the knowledge of good and evil? And are
angels still falling?"
>> So, do the angels have the knowledge of
good and evil? And are they still
falling, Brother Jerome?
Uh well let's deal with the um first
part of the question. Um do angels have
the knowledge of good and evil? Uh Satan
the devil is that serpent that knowledge
of that that that tree that had a
knowledge of good and evil. That's Satan
the devil. Okay. So right there it let
you know that yeah the fallen angels
have a knowledge of good and evil. And
the angels that followed Satan, they got
the same spirit. They had a knowledge of
good and evil, too. Okay? Uh but let's
go to 2 Corinthians chap 11,
and we going to read verse 13 and 14.
Go ahead when you get it.
For such are false apostles, deceitful
workers transforming themselves into the
apostles of Christ. Now these these
these these guys are being led, okay, by
Satan the devil and any of the angels
that follow Satan, the devil. All right.
He said, "But they are transformed
themselves into apostles of Christ. They
ain't apostle of Christ. They just
pretending." Right? So they know how to
do good.
Okay. But go ahead and read
>> and no marvel for Satan himself is
transformed into an angel of light.
>> Yeah. He he transformed too. And he and
then he put that spirit on his followers
whether they realize they following him
or not. Okay. So uh one more place and
that'll be it. Let's go to Daniel's 8
cuz Satan and and you know he put this
spirit on the false prophet.
Okay,
is going and he's he going he going to
really put it on him in the latter day.
But let's go take a look at it.
Daniel's 8 read verse 23-2.
Okay.
It says,
"And in the latter time of their
kingdom, when the transgressors are come
to the full, a king of fierce
countenance and understanding dark
sentences shall stand up."
>> In Revelation, it said that uh the
dragon gave him gave him his seat
and uh great authority and power. Yeah.
Go ahead. and his power shall be mighty,
but not by his own power. And he
>> it's by the power of Satan. You know,
Lord going to allow it in in in a latter
day. Go ahead.
>> And he shall destroy wonderfully
>> and shall prosper and practice and shall
destroy the mighty and the holy people.
>> Mhm. And through his policy also he
shall cause craft to prosper in his
hand.
>> And he shall magnify himself in his
heart and by peace shall destroy many.
He shall also stand up against the
prince of princes, but he shall be
broken without hand.
>> Notice in that verse 25 he said by peace
he going to destroy many. So he going to
deceive him with that peace, but his
intentions is to destroy because he is a
destroyer. That's all I got on.
>> All right, thank you for that. We hope
that answers your question as we move on
to our next one.
>> Moving on. Ba asks, "With the feast of
trumpets coming up, can you please
explain what trumpets we are
celebrating?
the seven trumpets in Revelation or the
trumpets of numbers in 10.
>> I'm sorry. I'm sorry, brother Cornell. I
forgot to answer the last part of that
question. Forgive me.
>> In the last part of the first question,
uh, are angels still falling? No, they
fell way back there. You can read it in
Genesis. Okay. They they they they been
failed. So they not still falling. Okay?
And if you read that Revelations 12
verse 7-9, it'll let you know. It'll let
you know that God had Michael and his
angels throw out Satan and his angels on
down to this earth. All right. And they
walking to and fro right now seeking
whom they may devour.
>> That's all I got. Sorry about that.
>> Yeah. No, that was a good catch,
brother. We're glad you caught that. And
uh therefore we hope that that answered
their question as we move on to the one
that uh is number two.
>> And again for number two BA asks with
the feast of trumpets coming up. Can you
please explain what trumpets we are
celebrating? The seven trumpets in
Revelations or the trumpets of Numbers
10. All right. So, Julius, they talking
about the celebration of trumpets. We
know we got a trumpet coming out this
year, but what say you?
>> Well, we going to see what say the book.
The first of all, neither says neither.
We're not celebrating. We're not
celebrating neither. The feast of the
memorial of trumpets is a memorial or a
reminder of something in the end time in
the future. Let's go to Numbers the 10th
chapter
and we're going to read James verses 1
and two. Numbers 10:es 1 and two. Let me
show you what the trumpets are are for
because only the priest blow the
trumpets.
Numbers 10. Now let's pay attention to
what these trumpets for. We are a
scattered nations. Okay? We're in
captivity. No matter what nobody say as
a nation we're in captivity.
Uh this is for back then. Numbers 10 and
1 and2. When you get it, brother James,
read it.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
Make thee two trumpets of silver, of a
whole piece shalt thou make them, that
thou mayest use them for the calling of
the assembly, and for the journeying
of the camps.
>> Two. So now that's what that was back in
the ancient days. The priest would blow
the trumpets for the calling to gather
the people together and to when to pitch
the camp, when to set up and when to
move. Okay. So now
let's go to Leviticus 23rd chapter.
And this is what we're waiting on. And
this is why we have the memorial of
blowing a trumpet. It's a memorial. It
is to be done when the Lord say do it.
Leviticus 23 verse
uh 4.
They're listed upon the feast of the
Lord. But read verse four. Let's get to
the point.
>> These are the feasts of the Lord, even
holy convocations which ye shall
proclaim in their seasons.
>> In their seasons. Skip down to verse 24,
James, and read it.
Speak unto the children of Israel,
saying, In the seventh month, and the
first day of the month shall ye have a
Sabbath, a memorial of blowing of
trumpets and holy convocation.
>> So it is a memorial to be done in the
seventh month, sisters and brothers, in
the first day of the month, what we call
the memorial of blowing of trumpets. But
what do those trumpets really
represents? Let's go to Revelation the
8th chapter.
Seven trumpets must be blown
all the way from the first one to the
seventh which announces world events,
things that are going to happen in
certain parts of the world. Revelation
8, Revelation 8, James, read verse two.
And I saw the seven angels which stood
before God, and to them were given seven
trumpets.
>> Now you got seven angels. See, men blew
the trumpet. The priest of God blew the
trumpets. But now when the all this is
culminating to all the way up to the
return of the Lord to take over the
kingdoms of this world, angels are going
to blow these trumpets. Skip down to my
brother. Skip down to verse six. Go
ahead. And the seven angels which had
the seven trumpets prepared themselves
to sound.
>> So the brothers asking where are we
celebrating? Are we celebrating? And
what trumpet? That's what basically he's
asking. What trumpet are we are we
celebrating? None of them. Because the
angels are going to do this. Verse
seven. Read it. Now you tell me. Has
this happened yet? Cuz this is yet
future events. Go ahead.
The first angel sounded and there
followed hell and fire mingled with
blood and they were cast upon the earth
and the third part of trees was burnt up
and all green grass was burnt up. So
this is yet future all of these all the
way all the way to the seventh trumpet
sounding which is revelation um the uh
11th chapter verse 15. The seventh
trumpet announces the return of the Lord
to take over the kingdoms of this world.
So we are observing the memorial of
trumpets which represents when the seven
angels begin in the sound which is will
culminate all the way up to the return
of the Lord. You could read Revelation
to get all seven of them read Revelation
89 and then Revelation 11 chapter which
is the seven trumpet sounding. So
therefore that's what those mean
Cornell. So we're not uh celebrating any
of it. We're keeping the memorial of
blowing the trumpets as a commandment
which represents when the Lord come uh
uh before he comes the seven angels got
to sound.
So
>> we don't do those things today. We just
do those things as a memorial each year.
Just like the Passover represents the
Lord passing over in every generations
the sins of the people in every
generation all the way up until the when
the Lord come. I hope that helped.
>> Yep. And um also I'd like to add to
that.
>> Yes. Caller.
>> Answer ask the question again. What did
the question?
>> Right. Because the question is
uh this person wants to know why do we
celebrate memorial blowing of trumpets?
That's his question. Why do we celebrate
it?
>> Okay. Well, you just gave a answer a
whole lot. He answered the question, but
I like simplicity.
The reason we celebrate it is to remind
us and the whole world that the Lord
going to come and he going to have seven
angels with seven trumpets.
>> Mhm. And each trump is going to call
some kind of drummer on this earth which
is is announced as the vile of wrath.
And every time a trumpet blow the other
angel going to bring some wrath upon
this earth. So the simple answer is they
rep they remind us
that the Lord going to have seven
trumpets blown
and each one of them trumpets is going
to bring some drum up on this earth. And
when the seventh trumpet is blown, then
that's going to bring the Lord. It's
going to be and it's going to announce
the first resurrection.
That's when the Lord's going to take
over this earth. Going to come and take
it over this earth. So the seven trumpet
represent the time when the Lord is
going to take down this earth
by having seven trumpets bring seven
vows of wrath upon this earth. Okay.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
And um then also I'd like to add to that
if you like a more indepth look on
September the 23rd at 12:00 noon we'll
be having a more indepth lesson titled
the memorial of the blowing of the
trumpets. So please feel free to join us
so that you can get a more in-depth look
on why we do it according to what thus
says the Lord. All right, we hope that
answered your question as we continue to
move on to our next one.
Next one. Jennifer Love asks,
"Scriptures that reference our works w
ks in quotations.
>> Is this talking about helping others,
charitable contributions,
or sharing the truth and bringing others
into the true word of God?"
>> All right. When we see here, you said
scriptures that reference works and is
this talking about? Well, there's good
works and there's bad works. But what
you got listed here, helping others,
that can be good work. Charitable
contributions, good work. Sharing the
truth, definitely. And bringing others
into the true word of God, that is also
good works. And keeping the commandments
of God, like the Lord say, if you love
me, keep my commandments. That is a
great work there. But let's go into um
Luke 10 and let's pick up a conversation
that Jesus was having himself when he
was here. Let's go into that Luke 10.
And somebody had came up and asked him,
tempting him, asking what can they do to
inherit eternal life. And let's see the
good that the Lord say he should bring
forth. Luke 10 and let's pick it up at
verse 25. Go ahead.
And behold, a certain lawyer stood up
and tempted him, saying, "Master, what
shall I do to inherit eternal earth?"
Mean eternal life.
>> eternal life. Yep.
>> He He said he said unto him, "What is
written in the law, how readest thou?"
>> And the Lord asked him, "Hey, what's
written in the law? And what readest
thou? What this man say?" And he
answering said, "Thou shalt love the
Lord thy God with all thy heart, and
with all thy soul, and with all thy
strength, and with all thy mind, and thy
neighbor as thyself."
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he said unto him, "Thou has answered
right. This do, and thou shalt live."
>> Yes. because it's a whole lot of good
works in what this guy said that he knew
that was written in the law. And the
Lord told him, "Hey, you answered that
question right. Do that and thou shalt
live." Because when you love the Lord
with all your heart, with all your soul,
with all your strength, and with all
your mind, he is number one in your
life. And you going to do the best you
can to please him and to do the things
that he say. Let's go into um
Ecclesiastes 12 because I just wanted to
show you just mentioned works but there
are good works and there can also be
some bad works. those you want to stay
away from.
>> Ecclesiastes,
>> the 12th chapter,
>> chapter
and also make sure that you are are
reading this book so that you can
further edify yourself with what thus
says the Lord. Let's go to that verse
nine and we going to do some skipping.
Go ahead. And moreover, because the
preacher was wise, he still taught the
people knowledge. Yay, he gave good heed
and sought out and set in order many
proverbs.
>> So another good work of you is, hey, you
should be getting taught by a teacher
that is wise, that has read this book,
that know what he talking about, that he
can give knowledge and good heed, and he
studies this book to bring it forward
unto the people. Because some preachers
are not wise at all. Skip down, brother,
and read uh verse 13 and 14.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments, for this is the whole duty
of man.
>> Loaded with good works. Go ahead. For
God shall bring every work into judgment
with every secret thing, whether it be
good or whether it be evil. So whether
it be good works or evil, hey, God going
to bring all of that in the judgment. So
load yourself up with as many good works
as possible so you can save yourself
from this untored generation. That's all
I got.
And we hope that that answered your
question as we continue to move on to
our next
>> next one. Nazia Monae asks, "Can you
light frankincense and myrr on the
Sabbath?"
>> Oh, and that question right there, you
kind of answered it yourself. Can you
light? And the answer is no. You cannot
light. You want your house to smell all
good, you got to do it six days a week,
but not on the Lord's Sabbath day. Let's
go into that Exodus 35.
Exodus 35
and let's see what was said right here
as Moses gathered all the congregation
of the children together and said unto
them the words of the Lord. Verse one,
brother.
And Moses gathered all the congregation
of the children of Israel together, and
said unto them, These are the words
which the Lord hath commanded that ye
should do them.
>> Mhm.
>> Sixth day shall work be done, but on the
seventh day there shall be to you an
holy day, a Sabbath of rest to the Lord.
Whosoever doeth work therein shall be
put to death.
Go ahead. Don't play. Go ahead.
>> Ye shall kindle no fire throughout your
habitations upon the Sabbath day.
>> That's your answer right there. You
shall kindle no fire throughout your
habitations upon the Sabbath day, also
known as the seventh day of the week. So
no, you cannot light frankincense and
myrr on the Sabbath day. But on the
other six days, hey, feel free, but not
on the Lord's Sabbath day. That's all I
got.
And we're going to keep it rolling from
there, Sister Deborah.
>> Yes. Let's move on. Jennifer Love says,
"I would like to know if the guest
caller has read articles written by
Herbert Armstrong,
and I'm just curious if the man was
taught by an Israelite." One of my
coworker is constantly talking about
Armstrong.
>> All right. Herbert Armstrong guest
caller.
>> But the first thing is no Israelite
taught Herbert Armstrong. And
Armstrong's whole doctrine is built on a
lie.
He says that Ephraim and Manasseh is
England in America
>> and that the queen of England is sitting
on David's throne and he go to Jeremiah
the 33rd chapter to try and and quote
where the Lord said the days going to
come when David shall never want a man
to sit up on his throne but they never
finish it and then sh and the and the
and the preach the Levites and never
fail to make offering before me First
thing is uh uh show you how uninformed
Armstrong is. But I don't I don't blame
him because he's a gentile. He said the
queen of England is sitting on David's
throne. But the whole thing is
if she is Ephraim, when is it that
Ephraim is going to sit on David's
throne?
Never.
Second thing is America and the
Commonwealth of uh uh uh uh uh England,
the British is not in the Bible.
The British was almost a part of it, but
then they got out of the common market.
They are not in the Bible.
And when the book said David should
never want a man to sit on his throne,
he is talking about when Jesus came back
because Armstrong had messed that thing
up when he said that the Lord is going
to overturn, overturn and over overturn
it. That's talking about the the throne
of David and it shall be no more until
he come until he come whose right it is
which is talking about Jesus. Mhm.
>> Then it said that the Lord that the Lord
going to take a a a twig, a tender one
from a high twig. That's the royal sea.
And that's talking about the queen of
England. That is the biggest lie ever
been told. Armstrong is a gentile
and God say showed his word to Israel,
not Gentile. They are gentile. They are
not Israelites. And the truth, the truth
of the matter is it embarrasses me to
even think that a Israelite with some
knowledge would even think that
Armstrong has some understanding. He
have none.
And when it come down to uh uh uh I want
you to go and read uh uh you know in
Leviticus the in Leviticus the 16th
chapter
it tells you about the uh two lambs.
Let's read a little bit there. Let's go
into Leviticus the 16th chapter.
>> Okay.
>> I'm there.
>> Okay. We we we going to start reading at
verse uh verse one 16 and one. Okay. Go
ahead.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses after the
death of the two sons of Aaron when they
offered before the Lord and died.
>> Go ahead. And the Lord said unto Moses,
"Speak unto Aaron thy brother, that he
come not at all times into the holy
place within the veil before the mercy
seat, which is upon the ark."
>> Go ahead.
>> That he die not, for I will will appear
in the cloud upon the mercy seat.
>> Uhhuh. Thus shall Aaron Thus shall Aaron
come into the holy place with a young
bulock for a sin offering and a ram for
a burnt offering.
>> He shall put on the holy linen coat and
he shall have the linen breaches upon
his flesh and shall be girded with the
linen girdle with the linen mait shall
he be attired. These are holy garments.
Therefore shall he wash his flesh and
water and so put them on.
>> Go ahead.
>> And he shall take of the congregation of
the children of Israel two kids of the
goats for a sin offering and one ram for
a burnt offering.
and Aaron and Aaron shall offer his
bulock of the sin offering which is for
himself and make an atonement for
himself and for his house and and he
shall take the two goats and present
them before the Lord at the door of the
tabernacle of the congregation.
>> Now these two goats he going to get both
of them represent Jesus. Armstrong said
it's talking about Asel, some evil
spirit, especially the scapegoat. Keep
reading.
>> And Aaron shall cast lots upon the two
goats, one lot for the Lord, and the
other lot for the scapegoat.
And a and Aaron shall bring the goat
upon which the Lord's lot fell, and
offer him for a sin offering. But the
goat on which the lot failed to be the
scapegoat shall be presented alive
before the Lord to make an atonement
with him and to let him go for a
scapegoat into the wilderness.
>> Now this scapegoat he call how you going
how you going to uh uh uh make an
atonement for an unclean uh spirit or
evil spirit. Everybody say this this
this scapegoat represent some uh uh uh
uh a devil or Satan. This represent the
Lord. The one that was offered represent
the Lord uh uh uh uh blood
that's going to cleanse everybody. I
want you to skip down.
I want to skip down to uh uh uh uh
where he going to end up when when he's
going to make his offering. When he get
through sprinkling everything with the
blood, I'm going show you what he going
to do with this scapegoat. Let's see.
>> Is that verse 21?
>> 21. Let's see.
>> Yeah. Uh-huh.
>> Okay. Verse 21 says,
>> Mhm.
>> Wait a minute. Wait.
Read verse 20 to go into it. This is
when he get you dealing with the blood
and cleansing everything. Go ahead.
>> Okay. Verse 20 says, "And when he have
made an end of reconciling the holy
place and the tabernacle of the
congregation and the altar, he shall
bring the live goat. And Aaron shall lay
both his hands upon the head of the live
goat, and confess over him all the
iniquities of the children of Israel,
and all their transgressions, and all
their sins, putting them upon the head
of the goat, and shall send them away by
the hand of a fit man into the
wilderness.
>> Now, this wilderness represents heaven.
Now, who is it that the Lord put all the
sins on? Jesus. Jesus.
>> Let's go in Isaiah the 56th chapter
right quick.
>> Okay,
let me see. 56 or 53rd. Wait a minute.
Hold on a minute.
>> 53
>> because Huh? It's the 53rd. I think the
53rd chapter Isaiah. Let me see.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yeah. Isaiah 53 starting at verse one.
>> Isaiah 53 and1 says, "Who hath believed
our report and to whom is the arm of the
Lord revealed?
For he shall grow up before him as a
tender plant and as a root out of a
>> let me tell see he just as Jesus going
to grow up before him as a tender
plant." Understand? Understand this is
not they call this the tender ones. the
Queen of England. This is Jesus. Go
ahead and read.
>> And as a root out of a dry ground. He
hath no form nor cleanliness. And when
we shall see him, there is no beauty
that we should desire him.
He is despised
and rejected of men, a man of sorrows
and acquainted with grief. And we hid as
it were our faces from him. He was
despised and we esteemed him not.
Surely he hath borne our griefs and
carried our sorrows. Yet we did esteem
him stricken, smitten of God, and
afflicted.
But he was but he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our
iniquities. The chastisement of our
peace was upon him, and with his stripes
we are healed.
Go ahead.
>> All we like sheep have gone astray. We
have turned everyone to his own way. And
the Lord has laid on him the iniquity of
us all.
>> Isn't that what happened to the
scapegoat?
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
>> The priest put all iniquity on the head
of that goat. So Armstrong
uh talked that this is this is some kind
of devil or evil spirit that is Jesus.
It's all that simple. And the queen how
the queen of England if she was Ephraim,
how is it that the Ephraimite going to
sit on the throne of Judah? It is not
going to happen.
And when he said it throne and and and
when it come to I'm telling you his
teaching come the throne of David going
to be overturned overturned and
overturned and it should be no more
until he come who's right and ill. The
first time it was overturned with
Jehoakim.
>> Yep.
>> He did that which was evil in the sight
of the Lord. Then they put his son
Jehovah in char. God overturned that.
That's the second time.
And then Nebuchadnezzar sent and got him
and set up Zedekiah. And Ne God used
Nebuchadnezzar to overturn that. And the
throne is still no more and it will not
be no more until Jesus come.
>> That's right.
>> Armstrong.
He don't have a clue.
And frankly, it's an embarrassment to me
to even think that some Israelite taught
him when his whole doctrine is built on
the lie. That's all I got to say.
Oh, Cornell, you're on mute.
>> Our apology. Good example there of words
that are written, even words of truth.
We hope that answered your question as
we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Me too for you asks, "Why are
people thinking the rapture is coming
September the 24th? Should I try to say
something or just let them be? I feel
like Jeremiah, I want to say something.
>> So, guess caller, what is this about the
September 24th rapture that they talking
about is coming.
>> And let me tell you something. The years
ago, we had a preacher on the west side
of Chicago
and pick the date that the Lord was
going to come.
And he even bought some of the
properties from some of his members.
And so some of the brothers from the
Israel of God went over there on that
day and see if they was going to leave.
The rapture didn't happen.
>> So I'm going tell you why should you say
something? What you do is you just be
quiet.
>> Yep. Yeah.
>> And then on the on September the 24th,
no, September the 25th, you go over and
ask them, "Why are you still here?"
>> Yep.
>> That's all you.
>> Good question.
>> Okay. That's all I got to say.
>> All right. So, hope that answered your
question there. And uh, Sister Deborah,
next question with a time check.
>> Yes, next question. Time is 8:07.
Valencia wants explanation on Romans
4:es
4 and 5.
>> All right. Romans 4. 4 and five. What
you say, Dre?
>> I say, let's go pick that up and start
at verse three, brother. When you get
there, go ahead.
>> Romans 4:3 says, "For what said the
scripture? Abraham believed God, and it
was counted unto him for righteousness.
>> Now to him that workketh is the reward
not reckoned of grace, but of debt.
>> But to him that workketh not, but
believeth on him, that justifieth the
ungodly, his faith is counted for
righteousness.
Listen, Abraham believed God and it was
counted to him for righteousness. We are
going to look at how Abraham believed
God. But justification
comes by the blood of Jesus.
And it's not it doesn't end right there.
You believe and you got to walk in your
belief. But let's back up to the third
chapter and we gonna read something
there. Bag up to Romans 3 and pick it up
at verse 23.
>> Okay,
>> go ahead.
>> It says, "For all have sinned and come
short of the glory of God."
>> Mhm.
>> Being justified freely by his grace
through the redemption that is in Christ
Jesus.
>> Yes. whom God has set forth to be a
propitiation through faith in his blood
to declare his righteousness for the
remission of sins that are passed
through the forbearance of God. So this
uh
redemption, our justification is coming
by the blood of Jesus through faith in
his blood and to declare his
righteousness for remission of sins that
are passed. It says through his
forbearance.
Go ahead. Verse 26. to declare I say at
this time his righteousness that he
might be just and the justifier of him
which believeth in Jesus.
>> That's right. He we are justified
by believing in Jesus and what he did.
Now skip down to verse 31.
Go ahead.
>> Do we then make void the law through
faith? God forbid. Yay, we establish the
law.
>> So, we don't do away with the law
because we have faith. We establish the
law. Now, go to Hebrews the 11th chapter
and and start at verse 6. Hebrews 11 and
pick it up at verse 6 and we going to
skip. Go ahead.
>> It says, "But without faith it is
impossible to please him."
>> Uh-huh.
>> Right. For he that cometh to God must
believe that he is, and that he is a
rewarder of them that diligently seek
him.
>> So, we have to have faith, but we also
have to diligently
seek him. That's what the book says
right there. Skip down to verse eight,
brother. Go ahead.
By faith, Abraham, when he was called to
go out into a place where he should
after receive for an inheritance,
obeyed, and he went out, not knowing
whether he went.
>> That's right. Now, Abraham
Abraham had a working faith that was
bagged up by his obedience. Abraham
obeyed and went out because God told him
to
question it. Skip down to verse 17.
Verse 17.
By faith Abraham, when he was tried,
offered up Isaac. And he that had
received the promises offered up his
only begotten son. Go ahead. of whom it
was said that in Isaac shall thy seed be
called.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Accounting that God was able to raise
him up even from the dead from whence
also he received him in a figure.
Abraham's faith was so strong and his
works was manifested in his faith.
Abraham went to offer up his son.
>> Yeah.
>> It wasn't just I'm talking. Abraham had
a working faith. Let's go to one more
place. Let's go to James 2. James 2 and
we going to pick it up at verse 21.
James 2 and 21.
>> Go ahead.
>> James 2 and 21 says, "Was not Abraham
our father justified by works when he
had offered Isaac his son up I mean upon
the altar?" Mhm.
>> See, seeest thou how faith wrought with
his works, and by works was faith made
perfect.
>> By his works was his faith made perfect,
and faith was wrought with works. Go
ahead.
>> And the scripture was fulfilled which
saith, Abraham believed God, and it was
imputed unto him for righteousness, and
he was called the friend of God.
>> Go ahead. Ye see then how that by works
a man is justified and not by faith
only.
>> Not by faith only. Now I just got two
more verses. Bag up to verse 18. Read 18
and 19. That's it.
>> Yay. A man may say, "Thou has faith, and
I have works." Show me thy faith without
thy works, and I will show thee my faith
by my works.
>> Thou believe, thou believest that there
is one God. Thou doest will. The devils
also believe and tremble.
>> That's right. So, we are justified again
by the blood of Jesus. But after we get
that justification,
we have to have a working faith. And
that faith must be onto the end. That's
>> right.
>> And like the book says, receive in the
end of your faith, even the salvation of
your soul.
>> Yeah.
>> That's what happens at the end. That's
all I got.
>> Hey, um, is it all right if I add that
Genesis 26, Brother Dre?
>> Absolutely.
>> And verse five. Just just verse five.
>> Genesis 26
and verse five says,
"Because that Abraham obeyed his voice,
obeyed my voice and kept my charge, my
commandments, my statutes, and my laws."
>> Yeah. Working faith.
>> That's right. Thank you, brother Jerome.
Excellent, brother. Yes.
>> Yes, sir. Yes sir.
>> Can I can I intervene? But not in that.
>> Yes sir.
>> Uh yeah. I left you know a part of that
thing about Armstrong. They they said
did the guest caller read uh uh any
articles written by Herban Armstrong.
So I didn't answer that question is
guest caller did read some of his
literature. In fact, he read his book
called The United States and Common and
British Commonwealth in Prophecy. Yes,
the United States
and British Commonwealth in Prophecy.
The title itself is a lie. The United
States is not in prophecy and neither is
the British Commonwealth. In fact, the
whole book is based on a lie. Okay,
that's all I got to say.
>> Yes, sir. All right. All right. So that
was more edification.
That was more edification on one of our
previous questions that was a asked
there. And the question that Dre and
Jerome chimed in is that hey, you can
have all the faith in the world, but you
got to have some works to go with it.
Right, brothers?
>> Yes, sir, brother.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Yes, sir. And keeping them commandments
and laws and stuff. Hey, then we also
would be the friend of God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. Praise the Lord. Okay, sister
Deborah, we moving on.
>> Yes, we're moving on. And with the guest
caller uh speaking about Armstrong, the
question was uh was he taught by uh an
Israelite and had he read any of the
articles written by Herbert Armstrong?
So, uh the guest caller answered those
questions. So, moving on. Kylie Parker
says in
1 Timothy 2 11 and 12, I know it means
women can't preach from a pulpit, but
does it also mean women can't partake in
any sorts of leadership roles as well?
example being a chairwoman, being a
manager, being a congresswoman,
being a ruler, etc. So, can a woman
partake can partake in any other
leadership roles?
>> Brother Julius, what you say?
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. She can take in
uh uh in other leadership roles, you
know, and the question is really
answered in the first part of that
question, you know, cuz we can read.
Let's go to first Timothy. Let's go to
that 1 Timothy. James,
>> I'm there.
>> 1 Timothy 2, read verse 11 to 12.
>> Let the woman learn in silence with all
subjection.
>> Uh-huh.
>> But I suffer not a woman to teach, nor
to usurp authority over the man, but to
be in silence.
>> That's when it comes to uh uh trying to
get behind the pull pit. That's not the
woman's place. But in other works, in
other things, she could take uh uh uh uh
she could help work in the ministry.
Um
Deborah was a judge. Miriam and Holder
were both prophetesses. Esther was
queen. Phoebe uh was Paul's
assistant. She was a ministry. Uh uh uh
she was uh uh she worked in the
ministry. Let's go to Romans 16 because
now they got these new Bibles out that's
trying to make Phoebe a deaconess
or a preacher. Let's go to Romans the
16th chapter and let's look at what Paul
said. This is why you got to be careful
with some of these other Bibles because
uh and everybody wants to be all
inclusive but God is God and he set the
precedence.
He set the precedence. But male and
female
uh ministries are started not are
started by uh organizations and not God.
Read Romans 16. Read verse 1 to3. Romans
16 1-3. When you get it, go ahead,
James.
>> I com I command unto you, Phoebe, our
sister, which is a servant of the
church, which is at Centuria. Now, now
some of these new Bibles got her as a
deaconess and they said that means
deaconess. That can't be. Finish it,
brother.
>> That ye receive her in the Lord as
become saints, and that ye assist her in
whatsoever business she hath need of
you, for she hath been a secure of many,
and of myself also.
>> She's taking care of a lot of people uh
that in the ministry. Go ahead to verse
three. Greet Priscilla and Aquilla, my
helpers in Christ Jesus.
>> Now, that's a husband and wife team that
also helped Paul. Now, let's go back to
uh let's go to my last place, uh 1
Timothy the 3 chapter
because they want to make women
deaconesses. Now, now they want to make
women bishops. That's out of that's out
of order. 1 Timothy 3, read one and two,
James. 1 Timothy 3 1 and two. One and
two. Go ahead.
>> This is a true saying. If a man desireth
office, if a man
>> Uhhuh.
>> desire the office of a bishop, he
desireth a good work.
>> Go ahead.
>> A bishop that must be blameless. The
husband of one wife.
>> Can't be no woman. Have to be a man. Go
ahead.
Viligent, sober, of good behavior, given
to hospitality, apt to teach.
>> But what if, but what if the woman wants
to be a deaconess? Verse 12, what does
it say?
>> Let the deacons be the husbands of one
wife.
>> No, the deacons be the wives of one
husband.
>> Let the deacons be the husbands of one
wife, ruling their children and their
own houses. Well,
>> so therefore, when it comes to the
ministry, the men as the the the pastors
and the deacons and the bishops are
always men. But in the world and doing
business and stuff, we got uh a woman
can be vice president. She could be a
high office executive. She could be a
judge. We got judges on the Supreme
Court of the United States. You know, we
and you had a queen that just died,
Queen Elizabeth. So there's nothing
wrong with those, but when it comes to
the church, she cannot be behind the
pull pit. That's all I got.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question there. And uh we have a lot of
women too in the military that's doing
some important positions as well.
>> Exactly.
>> All right, Sister Deborah. Time check
with our next one.
>> Time is 8:21.
Stephen Guggis asks
in Acts 18
19 through 21, why didn't the people who
were Jews go with Paul to go to the
feast of tabernacles when he left for
Jerusalem?
Were there Jews? Were these Jews
non-believers?
>> All right. So, we know Paul kept these
feasts. What you say Jerome?
>> Uh let's go read the verse uh that you
gave uh Acts the 18th chapter verse 19-
21.
>> It says, "And he came to Ephesus and
left them there. But he himself entered
into the synagogue and reasoned with the
Jews.
When they desired him to tar longer time
with them, he consented not, but bathed
them farewell, saying, I must be by all
means keeping this feast that cometh in
Jerusalem, but I will return again unto
you if God will. And he sailed from
Ephesus.
>> Okay. Um,
we really can't make the determination
um that they didn't go to Jerusalem just
because they didn't go with Paul.
You know what I'm saying?
>> They could at another time with somebody
else.
All that is still speculation. So, the
answer to the question is we don't know
if they went to Jerusalem or not because
it don't say.
>> Okay. So, uh, but those that have
understanding and
are going to serve the true and living
God and keep his commandments,
they know to go at when it's the season
to go for whatever feast that's supposed
to be kept. Okay. So, let's go to
Deuteronomy the 16th chapter
and we're going to read verse 13-
16.
Okay. Deuteronomy 16
13-16
says, "Thou shalt observe the feast of
tabernacles 7 days. After that thou has
gathered in thy corn and thy wine.
And thou shalt rejoice in thy feast,
thou and thy son, and thy daughter, and
thy man's servant, and thy maid servant,
and the Levite, the stranger, and the
fatherless, and the widow that are
within thy gates. Seven days shalt thou
keep a solemn feast unto the Lord thy
God, in the place which the Lord shall
choose, because the Lord thy God shall
bless thee in all thy increase, and in
all the works of thine hands, therefore
thou shalt surely rejoice.
Three times in a year shall all males
appear before the Lord thy God in the
place which ye shall choose. In the
feast of the unleavened bread, and in
the feast of weeks, and in the feast of
tabernacles, and they shall not appear
before the Lord empty.
>> That's all I got.
>> Yes.
Yes, sir. Jerome. Hey, it's like Paul
say, I must by all means.
So if that applied to him, it applies to
even those of today, don't it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next question. He also asks in 2
Chronicles 36:E9
it says Jehoakim was Jehovah Chim was 8
years old when he began to reign as
king. I heard that this is a typo and
that 8 years old should be 18 years old.
Are there other scriptures that confirm
that?
All right, Julius. 8 vers 18.
>> Let's go, brother James to second 2
Chronicles 36.
>> I'm there.
>> I want you to read something real real
simple. Read
verse, go to 35.
Second Chronicles 35.
Okay,
>> let's get something established here.
>> Read verse 26. 2 Chronicles 35 and 26.
Now, we read we started in 2 Chronicles.
We're going to read 2 Chronicles because
the the person asking the question is
referring to 2 Chronicles 36. Let's 2
Chronicles 35. Read verse 26.
Now the rest of the acts of Josiah and
his goodness according to that which was
written in the law of the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And his deeds first and last. Behold,
they are written in the book of the
kings of Israel and Judah.
>> Now I want you to highlight that they
are written in the books of kings of
Israel and Judah. Now chapter 36 verse
8.
>> Now the rest of the acts of Jehookim and
his abominations which he did that which
was found in him. Behold, they are
written in the book of the kings of
Israel and Judah. Jehoachin.
>> Yeah. Jehoachin.
>> His son reigned in his steed.
>> Continue to read about the question
that's asked. Now go ahead.
Jehoachin was 8 years old when he began
to reign. And he reigned three months
and 10 days in Jerusalem. And he did
that which was evil in the sight of the
Lord.
>> Now we need to find out where Jehoatin
is written in the books of the kings.
Let's go to second Kings chapter 24.
Now pick this up at verse 8. Jehovah 10.
Read it.
>> Jehoachin was 18 years old when he began
to rain.
>> And he reigned in Jerusalem.
>> 18 years old.
>> He's 18 years old. Go ahead.
>> I'll take it back from the top. Jehoach
Chin was 18 years old when he began to
reign. And he reigned in Jerusalem 3
months. and his mother's name was
Nehusta, the daughter of El Nathan of
Jerusalem.
>> So now all of this has happened under J
under Nebuchadnezzar's watch cuz
Nebuchadnezzar came and conquered Judah.
If you want another reference, we don't
have to go there. You could read
Jeremiah the 22nd chapter. Well, before
his name was uh uh uh uh uh Jehoah 10,
his name was Jeaniah,
but Jeremiah the 22nd called him Jehiah
on your own. That's another reference if
you want to read it, but it's the same
story talking about the same king, this
king Jehoakin. So, the scripture is
right at 18 years old.
That's why I started it off as it is
written in the book of the kings.
Chronicle and kings mirror each other
but there are that is indeed a
typographical error. It should not be 8
years old. It should be indeed 18 years
old. That's all I got. Cornell.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Moving on. MJ asks, "What is meant by
white and ruddy in Songs of Solomon 5
10? Is it pertaining to color or is it a
metaphor?"
>> All right, that's Songs of Solomon 5 and
verse 10. They want to know is it
pertaining to color or is it a metaphor?
Let's go there, James.
>> I'm there.
>> All right. You got Proverbs,
Ecclesiastes, then you have the Songs of
Solomon. Pick it up at verse 10.
Chapter 5, verse 10. And the guest
caller will take it from there.
>> Okay. It says, "My beloved is white and
ruddy, the chiefest among 10,000."
>> That's a metaphor. Keep reading. His
head is as the most fine gold. His locks
are bushy and black as a raven.
His eyes are as the eyes of doves by the
rivers of waters washed with milk and
and fitly set.
His cheeks are as a bed of spices as
sweet flowers. His lips like lilies
dropping sweet smelling myrr. His hands
are as gold rings set with the burl. His
belly is as bright ivory overlaid with
sapphires. His legs are as pillars of
marble set upon sockets of fine gold.
His countenance is as Lebanon, excellent
as the cedars. His mouth is most sweet.
Yay, he is altogether lovely. This is my
beloved and this is my friend, oh
daughters of Jerusalem.
>> Now you seen anybody look like that?
>> No sir.
>> No.
>> It was a metaphor. Just letting you know
that the define and just like all these
sweet and and and goodlooking things
her love is like you say alltogether
lovely cuz the belove she talking about
is Jesus
>> that's a metaphor.
>> Yes sir. Inside of that metaphor is some
sweet rap. Boy them words are sweet
there. All right. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. As time is a ticking, Sister
Deborah, what time?
>> Yes, the time is ticking. And with
Robert Do question, I don't understand
how he asked this question or how to uh
ask it. I'm just going to read what the
question says. It says Romans 7 speaks
of save people of God still sin. Is this
right?
>> All right, brother Dre. We know we got
to condense it down because we ain't
going to read the whole Romans 7. What
you say, brother?
>> Yeah. Well, first of all, I want to let
him know that he that endures until the
end, the same shall be saved.
>> Let's go read that real quick.
Uh, Matthew 24 and 13. Matthew 24 and
13.
>> Okay. Matthew 24 and 13 says,
"But he that shall endure until the end,
the same shall be saved."
>> So this this
uh speaks of saved people of God still
sinning. Is that right? You know, hey,
you got to endure. And as long as you in
this fight, you are at war. The flesh
against the spirit and the spirit
against the flesh. And in that war, you
may you may fall cuz the book say a
righteous. Let's go read that too. Let's
go to Proverbs. Uh
Proverbs
20.
What is it? Proverbs
Proverbs 24. We going to read verse 16.
Proverbs 24 and 16.
>> It says, "For a just man fallth seven
times and riseth up again, but the
wicked shall fall into mischief."
>> That's right. So, a a just man going to
fall. He may fall seven times, but he
going to get back up. but to just fall
into mischief and stay there. Now, let's
go to that Romans and we going to
condense that a little bit. Romans, pick
it up at Romans 7 and read verse 7 and
we'll skip Romans 7 and 7. It says,
"What shall we say then? Is the law sin?
God forbid. Nay, I had not known sin but
by the law. For I had not known lust
except the law had said, "Thou shalt not
covet."
>> First John 3:4 tells us, "Sin is the
transgression of the law." The law is
not sin. Sin is breaking the law. And
Paul is saying here, I didn't know uh
what sin was except the law showed me. I
didn't know what lust was. Uh thou shalt
not covet. Skip down to verse 12,
brother. Go ahead.
>> Wherefore the law is holy, and the
commandment holy, and just, and good.
>> Now, skip down to verse 13.
>> Was then that which is good made death
unto me? God forbid. But sin, that it
might appear sin, workketh death in me
by that which is good. that sin by the
commandment might become exceeding
sinful.
>> So when the commandment came, it made
sin exceeding sinful.
Verse 14, go ahead.
>> For we know that the law is spiritual,
but I am carnal, sold under sin.
>> And that is the war. That's what we got
going on. Verse 18 and 19. Go ahead. For
I know that in me, that is, in my flesh,
dwelleth no good thing. For to will is
present with me. But how to perform that
which is good, I find not.
>> Uh-huh. Go ahead.
>> For the good that I would, I do not. But
the evil which I would not, that I do.
>> Skip down to verse 21 and read 22.
I find then a law that when I would do
good, evil is present with me. For I
delight in the law of God after the
inward man.
>> So he's saying, I delight in the law of
God after the inward man, but I find
that a law when I would do good, evil is
present with me. Verse 25 and that's it.
Go ahead.
I thank God through Jesus Christ our
Lord. So then with the mind I myself
serve the law of God but with the flesh
the law of sin.
>> Yeah. And the wages of sin is death. So
if you do a can a a person that know the
word of God sin? Yes he can.
But if he lay there, he gonna face a
judgment just like anybody else. But if
he repents and turn, he got a chance
because the book tell us that a living
dog is better than a dead lion.
>> And as long as you in this fight, you
can win. Just walk in faith.
>> That's that's all I got.
>> Yes, sir. Be strong and walk in this.
>> Yes. caller.
>> First thing I like to make a correction
to this thing. There is no saved people.
>> Oh, that's right.
>> He that endure to the end that's saved.
Just like you said, but it's something
too I want to throw in. Go to Hebrews
the 10th chapter and read verse 26 and
27.
>> That's right. Okay.
>> Hebrews 10 26 and 27 say, "For if we sin
willfully, after that we have received
the knowledge of the truth, there
remainth no more sacrifice for sins, but
a certain fear for looking for judgment
and fiery indignation, which shall
devour the adversaries."
>> So surely saying, "You can say it, but
not intentionally. But if you go out
there and say it intentionally
after you know better, then that's
what's waiting on you, waiting on you to
liquify.
>> Yes, sir. We don't want that. All right,
we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Bertha Cotton Smith says,
"If I am invited to a birthday party on
the Sabbath day,
would it be wrong
if if on my way to church I drop the
food off and after it is over, can I eat
clean food that was cooked on the
Sabbath? My family don't understand why
I can't eat food cooked on the Sabbath.
Please give me some scriptures to share
with them to help them understand.
>> All right, guest caller.
>> Let's go to Exodus 35th chapter. Read
verses 1-4.
>> Okay. Exodus 35:es
1-4 say, "And Moses gathered all the
congregation of the children of Israel
together, and said unto them, these are
the words which the Lord hath commanded
that ye shall do them. Sixth day shall
work be done, but on the seventh day
there shall be to you an holy day, a
Sabbath of rest. Whosoever doeth work
therein shall be put to death.
Ye shall kindle no fire throughout your
habitations upon the Sabbath day. And
Moses spake unto all the congregation of
the children of Israel, saying, "This is
the thing which the Lord commanded,
saying,"
>> Now, in order for you to cook, you got
to kill the fire, don't you?
>> Yep.
>> Mhm.
>> Yes. Let's go into uh Exodus the 16th
chapter and read verse 23.
>> Okay. Exodus 16 and 23 says, "And he
said unto them, this is that which the
Lord has said, tomorrow is the rest of
the holy Sabbath unto the Lord. Bake
that which ye will bake today and see
that ye sh will se and that which
remainth over lay up for you to be kept
until the morning.
>> So you have to do all your cooking and
your seasoning and your boiling or
whatever you got to do to prepare your
food before the Sabbath day. Then you
can eat that on the Sabbath. But if you
prepared eat uh uh food by prepared by
you or anybody else on the Sabbath day,
you're violating.
>> Yep.
>> But you ain't supposed to
fire on the Sabbath day. That's all I
got to say.
>> All right.
And it looks like in that question too,
they were asking that if they go over
there after the Sabbath is over and they
know that food was cooked during the
Sabbath, can they eat the food now that
the Sabbath is over?
>> Yeah, they violating.
>> Hold on.
>> All right.
>> All that prepared on the Sabbath day is
cooked on the Sabbath day.
>> Yep. So, all right. That answer your
question there. And yeah, Deborah, it's
a violation.
All right, let's move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Cassio Lee uh wants you
to explain Genesis 9 vers 1-6.
>> Oh, Genesis 9 1-6. Let's open this up to
the panel. When you get there, Brother
James, let's go ahead and read that
because
this is going to be dealing with Noah
and God. Go ahead, brother.
>> All right. Genesis 9:es 1-6 says, "And
God blessed Noah and his sons, and said
unto them, Be fruitful and multiply, and
replenish the earth, and the fear of
you, and the dread of you shall be upon
every beast of the earth, and upon every
fowl of the air, upon all that moveth
upon the earth, and upon all the fishes
of the sea, into your hand are they
delivered." All right. After the after
the flood, brother James, go ahead.
>> Every moving thing that liveth shall be
meat for you. Even as the green herb
have I given you all things,
but flesh with the life thereof, which
is the blood thereof, shall ye not eat.
And surely your blood of your lives will
I require. At the hand of every beast
will I require it, and at the hand of
man, and at the hand of every man's
brother will I require the life of man.
Who so shedth man's blood, by man shall
his blood be shed. For in the image of
God made he man.
>> All right. Venus a panel question. Who
would like to chime in on that?
Because we know for sure that meat that
the the broker of peace between man and
beast was now done away with. Guess
caller
>> go to Genesis first chapter
read 20 uh uh 27 to 30.
>> Okay. Genesis 1:es 27 to30 say, "So God
created man in his own image, in the
image of God created he him, male and
female created he them. And God blessed
them. And God said unto them, "Be
fruitful and multiply, and replenish the
earth, and subdue it, and have dominion
over the fish of the sea, and over the
fowl of the air, and over every living
thing that moveth upon the earth." And
God said, "Behold, I have given you
every herb bearing seed, which is upon
the face of all the earth, and every
tree in which is the fruit of a tree
yielding seed. To you it shall be for
meat. To every beast of the earth, and
to every fowl of the air, and to
everything that creepeth upon the earth,
wherein there is life, I have given
every green herb for meat." And it was
so. And God saw everything that he had
made, and behold, it was very good.
>> So that's it.
>> Man was vegetarian.
Animals was vegetarian.
No, nothing or nobody ate meat.
Okay.
>> So now this man saying
this household when they come across the
flood, then God put meat on the table
for man. But he also he put man meat on
the table for the beast and that meat is
be man and other beast
>> right.
>> All it's really saying is all of a
sudden uh you can eat the beast and the
beast going to eat you and all them if
they get a chance they would do it but
just to tell the man but you don't eat
the blood. And the other is telling you
that uh uh that the Lord is putting the
uh uh uh disciplinary action of man in
the hand of man.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So somebody break the law, he ain't
going to shoot you with no uh uh uh
lightning bolt from heaven.
You going to break the law, then the man
is going to be the one that that put you
on trial. The man is going to punish
you. And anybody that kill then you
gonna be killed by a man.
>> All is simply saying.
>> Yep. And and we know too, G caller, he
going to put the pe he go to put the
peace back on the table between man and
beast down the road.
>> Oh yeah. Uhhuh. So when he come, he said
he gonna make a covenant with with the
beast for man. It ain't g and ain't
going to be no destruction.
>> That's right. You know, and and that's
when the lion is going to eat straw like
the lamb.
>> Yes, sir. Yes,
>> brother.
>> And so, and and ain't no beast are going
to attack man no more. But still, the
beast will still be on the table for man
though during that time.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> And let me let me throw something in
there. Uh because somebody tried to trap
me with a question, especially the meat
part of it. Well, you you uh you
shouldn't be eating meat. You shouldn't
be eating flesh. Let's The Lord told you
in that Genesis that it's going to be
the the the plants of the field and the
herbs of the field shall be meat. So, he
said you shouldn't eat that. You can't
you can't eat meat. Meat is anything
that you eat, sisters and brothers, not
just flesh. Let's go to Matthew the
third chapter. I got one script there.
Matthew 3
and just uh James just read verse four.
Matthew 3 and 4. This is what I use on
the brother when he tried to say uh uh
meat is just flesh. Go ahead and read
it.
>> And the same John had his raignment of
camels hair and a lethar girdle about
his loins and his meat was locust and
wild honey. that show you that whatever
you eat can be meat. That's all I got
with that.
>> Well, so the whole the whole thing is
that's why it said that the herb shall
be meat to man.
>> But when it come down to uh uh and and
and and herbs going to be meat to all
the beast also.
>> But we know that the herb. But then
again too when he say going to put meat
on the table
he said but don't eat the blood in it.
Herbs don't have blood.
>> Then a guy asked me one time tried to
say that same thing to me about see meat
don't mean flesh. And then I took him to
the 11th chapter of Leviticus and read
where the Lord said these shall be the
beast that you should eat. And I asked
him, "What part of this that you don't
what part of these should be the beast
that you should eat that you don't
understand?"
>> That's right.
>> Yep.
All right.
Hope that that answered your question
there, Sister Deborah. Time is ticking
as we go into another question.
>> Yes. Uh Kim Noel asks,
"When you say Moses was changing when
his face was shining, do you mean he was
changing in a spiritual being or just
taking on the characteristics of a
spiritual being?"
>> All right, guest Cara. We know his face
was beginning to shine and the change
was beginning to take place. gas caller.
>> But either way you look at it,
he was never the same.
>> Exodus 34.
>> Exodus 34 and read 29-35.
>> Okay. Exodus 34 29-35 says, "And it came
to pass when Moses came down from Mount
Si with the two tables of testimony in
Moses's hand when he came down from the
mount that Moses was not that the skin
of his face shone while he talked with
him."
>> Mhm. And when Aaron and all the children
of Israel saw Moses, behold, the skin of
his face shone, and they were afraid to
come nigh him. And Moses called unto
them, and Aaron and all the rulers of
the congregation returned unto him, and
Moses talked with them. And afterward
all the children of Israel came nigh,
and he gave them in commandment all that
the Lord had spoken with him in Mount Si
until Moses had and until Moses had done
speaking with them, he put a veil on his
face. But when Moses went in before the
Lord to speak with him, he took the veil
off until he came out. And he came out
and spake unto the children of Israel
that which he was commanded. And the
children of Israel saw the face of
Moses, that the skin of Moses's face
shown, and Moses put the veil upon his
face again until he went in to speak
with him.
>> So now
whether he was changing or taking on the
characteristic, even if you going to
take on the characteristics of
something, there have to be some change
involved. And I know there was one guy
that hung out with God for three 300
years and he changed them all together.
He not
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> So why couldn't that happen to Moses?
>> That's right.
>> Cuz he didn't hang out with him long
enough. That's all I got to say.
>> Yep. All right. Hope that answered your
question there, Sister Deborah. Let's
take a run into new territory.
>> Yes. We are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, August the 27th,
27, 2025.
Droy asks, "Who was the fourth man with
Shack, Meack, and Abedneo when they were
thrown in the furnace in Daniel 3 24 and
25?"
>> Was that holy angel? But let's go there
and read that. Then let's open it up to
the panel since we in new territory.
>> Daniel 3 and which verse?
>> Daniel 3 uh vers 24 and 25.
>> All right. When you get there, brother,
go right ahead. Pick it up at that verse
23.
>> Okay.
>> Go ahead.
And these three men, Shadrach, Meak, and
Abednego, fell down bound in the midst
of the burning fiery furnace. Then
Nebuchadnezzar the king was a stone a
stony, and rose up in haste, and spake,
and said unto his counselors, "Did not
we cast three men bound into the midst
of the fire?" They answered, and said
unto the king, "True, O king." He
answered and said, "Lo, I see four men
loose, walking in the midst of the fire,
and they have no hurt, and the form of
the fourth is like the son of God."
>> That was that angel right there with
them.
And did they ask for verse 26 or No,
>> no.
>> Okay. Well, that was an angel that was a
fourth
right there with them keeping that fire
from doing any hurt. And let's um
um let's read that verse 27 to see also
what this angel was doing while they was
in that fire. Go ahead.
And the princes, governors, and
captains, and the king's counselors,
being gathered together saw these men,
upon whose bodies the fire had no power,
nor was an hair of their head singed.
Neither were their coats changed, nor
the smell of fire had passed on them.
>> You know that had to be angel in there
with him, right, Jane?
>> Indeed. Verse 28. Read verse 28. all
that good stuff to take place. Go ahead,
keep reading.
>> Then Nebuchadnezzar spake and said,
"Blessed be the God of Shadrach,
Meshack, and Abednego, who has sent his
angel, and delivered his servants that
trusted in him, and have changed the
king's word, and yielded their bodies,
that they might not serve nor worship
any god except their own god."
>> Yes, sir.
Yep. And so therefore, yeah, go ahead,
guest call.
>> That answers the question.
>> Yep.
>> That's it. And them brothers endured and
read 30 since you there. What happened
since they endured that?
>> Then the king promoted Shadrach,
Meshack, and Abedneo in the province of
Babylon.
>> Man, ain't that something? go through
all that to think that you could lose
your life but you endured and now you
got a promotion and that's what we are
looking forward to promotion from the
flesh to the spirit of God
>> that's why you got to that's why you got
to keep on reading you will eventually
run to your answer
>> praise the Lord for that all right
sister Deborah next question
>> next question
Joby asks in judges 20 5 and 6. Can you
explain why the Levite man cut up his
concubine and sent her pieces to each of
the 12 tribes? Is it vengeance supposed
to be God's? Also, did God support this
act?
Judges 20 verses 5 and six.
>> All right. So when you get there,
brother, go ahead and read it cuz this
was definitely attention getter. Go
ahead.
>> Okay. Judges 20 5 and 6 says, "And the
men of Giba rose against me and beset
the house round about upon me by night,
and thought to have slain me, and my
concubine have they forced that she is
dead." And I took my concubine and cut
her in pieces and sent her throughout
all the country of the inheritance of
Israel. For they have committed lwdness
and folly in Israel.
>> Mhm. Open to the pan.
>> Well, the man did it to get their
attention.
>> Yes, he did. Think
>> about you. You got an arm in it and a
note. So, look what these guys did in
the Benj in Benjamin.
So they they murdered his wife,
>> bunch of sodomites. So now what was the
question?
>> The question was
um
can you explain why the Levite man cut
up his concubine and sent her pieces to
each of the 12 tribes?
And
uh also did God support this act?
>> Well, the whole thing is obvious. Why?
Cuz he wanted to get their attention
because it was a lewd act. It shouldn't
happen in Israel. And sure, God
supported it. Because he wiped out the
whole nation of Israel except what was
it? 600 men or 800 men trapped in the
mountain. 600. Yeah. And Benjamin. Yeah.
The Benjamites.
Benjamin, he killed the women everybody
except what I think it was 6 or 800 men.
>> Yep. 600.
>> In fact, in fact, to tell you the truth,
they had to let them uh Benjamite guys
steal uh they threw a party, a feast,
and let them guys come in and steal one
of their daughters cuz they had vowed
not to let none of the Benjamites have
their daughters,
>> right? But the reason they so they said
we cannot have a tribe missing in
Israel.
So yeah, God went along with it.
Otherwise, he wouldn't let him slaughter
all Israel, all the Benjamite except for
800 men.
>> Yeah.
>> Yep. You're right. And uh you know, it
was um to get their attention because
the brother said, "Man, this has never
been known to happen." Like you said,
getting a body part in the mail
>> or by cherry, as I would say.
>> Your adrenaline,
>> something got to be done. This is this
is an abominable act.
>> Yes.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. Indeed. Deborah, our final question
before we bring it to a close. One more.
>> All right. Uh Charlotte asks, "Would you
please provide scriptures
identifying who the tree of life is?"
>> Scripture identifying who the tree of
life is. Okay.
>> Metaphor for Jesus.
>> We can go in the beginning to Genesis,
right?
>> Yeah.
It's a metaphor for many of his titles.
>> So, what was the question again,
Deborah?
>> Uh, yes. Can you provide scriptures
identifying who the tree of life is?
>> All right.
John 3:16 tell you he's the tree of
life.
We can go into Genesis 2. Let's go there
first right quick. Genesis 2.
[Applause]
>> They said the tree the tree of life,
right, Devil?
>> Uh, yes. Who who who the tree of life
is?
>> All right.
Two and nine.
>> Okay.
And out of the ground made the Lord God
to grow every tree that is pleasant to
the sight and good for food. The tree of
life also in the midst of the garden and
the tree of knowledge of good and evil.
>> Tree of life in the midst of the garden
that was the Lord himself. And the tree
of the knowledge of good and evil was
Satan himself. And where' you say,
Julius? Oh, guest caller. Go right
ahead.
He should give some scripture about the
tree of life, right?
>> Yes.
>> Psalms 80 verse one.
>> Psalms 80 and1.
>> Psalms 80 and1 says, "Give ear, oh
shepherd of Israel, thou that leadest
Joseph like a flock, thou that dwellest
between the cherubims shine forth."
Psalm 99
and1.
>> Psalm 99 and1 says,
"The Lord reignth, let the people
tremble. He siteth between the
cherubims. Let the earth be moved."
>> So tree
of life is the Lord.
>> Yeah. That's why I say
>> between the 12 and he dwell between the
12 because since man sin
and and the Lord put the chair of angels
around him in Genesis the third chapter
even when they build the tabernacle of
the congregation in the temple they put
the ark of the covenant there then they
put the mercy seat on that ark of the
covenant and on each side of the mercy
seat they had chair of angels saying
that you don't have access to the tree
of life anymore.
So the tree of life
is Jesus.
>> That's right.
>> He tell you that in Revelation 27, too.
>> Yep. Revelation 22.
>> Revelation 2 and 7.
>> Oh, 2 and 7. Yeah. All right. Uh,
quickly, James, Revelation 2 and 7.
It says, "He that hath an ear, let him
hear what the Spirit saith unto the
churches. To him that overcomemeth will
I give to eat of the tree of life, which
is in the midst of the paradise of God."
>> That's the same tree of life that was in
the garden in Genesis the third chapter.
>> Yep. And one more, James. Revelation 22,
the last book in the Bible,
>> as Julius just read out of two.
Revelation 22, pick it up at that 12,
brother.
>> And behold, I come quickly, and my
reward is with me to give every man
according as his work shall be.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and
the end, the first and the last.
>> One more verse.
Blessed are they that do his
commandments, that they may have right
to the tree of life, and may enter in
through the gates into the city.
>> Yes, sir. So, there we go with some good
old scriptures on that tree of life.
>> And um we hope that you receive that and
we'd like to thank everybody. Sister
Deborah, what's our time check?
>> 9:05.
>> 9:05. We ran a little over, but we
enjoyed oursel taking part and being
with you this evening. And we thank you
all from all around the world who sent
in those questions. And if we didn't
answer it this week, please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah's going to
take it, put it in rotation, and we will
deal with that question next Wednesday
at the same time. So, until we all get
together again, be safe out there. Be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
James closes us out. Our Father, which
art in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven. Give us this day our
daily bread, and forgive us our debts as
we forget our debtors, and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. in Jesus
name we pray. Amen.